hostingzoom.com 2006-08-13

# Hosting Zoom - Privacy Policy

  | 

Effective Date: 11/01/2004 

By submitting an online order form, or by using Hosting Zoom’s service, Customer hereby agrees to the following Privacy Policy. Customer agrees that it shall comply with and require its end users to comply with this Privacy Policy, Hosting Zoom’s Terms of Service (TOS), Hosting Zoom’s Acceptable Use Policy (AUP), and Hosting Zoom’s No-Spam Policy (NSP). In this document, the word “Agreement,” with a capital “A,” refers to the TOS, the AUP, the NSP, and the Privacy Policy collectively.

Hosting Zoom, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.hostingzoom.com. Because Hosting Zoom wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.   
If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the Hosting Zoom Privacy Officer by e-mail at privacy@hostingzoom.com. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. 

**1\. Introduction.**

Hosting Zoom respects the privacy of every individual who visits its Web sites and uses its services. This privacy statement provides notice of the standards and terms under which Hosting Zoom protects the privacy of information supplied by visitors to sites on the World Wide Web that are owned and operated by Hosting Zoom, including www.hostingzoom.com. This privacy statement provides notice of our information collection practices and of the ways in which your information may be used. This policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to review this information.

**2\. Personally Identifiable Information.**

Hosting Zoom typically receives specific data about its Web site visitors only when such information is provided voluntarily, such as when our visitors request information, purchase or enroll for services, provide resume information for employment opportunities, or send us e-mail. Of course, some of these activities require that you give us information, such as when you make a purchase, use a credit card or electronic payment service to pay for Hosting Zoom services, submit your resume, or request certain types of information. 

We collect the following types of information about you.

| Contact Information  
---  
  
•

| Name  
  
•

| Company  
  
•

| Postal Address  
  
•

| City  
  
•

| State  
  
•

| Country  
  
•

| Zip code or postal code  
  
•

| Email address  
  
•

| Telephone number  
  
•

| Fax number  
  
•

| Internet domain name  
  |    
Financial Information  
  
•

| Credit or debit card information  
  
•

| Cardholder name  
  
•

| Card number  
  
•

| Type of card (e.g., Visa, Mastercard)  
  
•

| Expiration date  
  
•

| Security code  
  
•

| Paypal account information  
  
•

| Email address of PayPal account  
  |    
Verification Data  
  
•

| Internet Protocol (IP) address for fraud-prevention purposes  
  |    
Other Information  
  
•

| Social Security Number (SSN), Federal Employer Identification Number (F.E.I.N.), or other Tax I.D. Number (this is collected if you join our affiliate program, so that we can comply with United States federal income tax laws.  
  
When you provide personally identifiable information to Hosting Zoom through one of our Web sites, it will be used to fulfill your specific request. However, Hosting Zoom reserves the right, in its discretion, to send you bulletins and other important information about your Hosting Zoom services. 

Hosting Zoom currently only sends service communication e-mails through www.hostingzoom.com, and does not send marketing e-mails or newsletters through www.hostingzoom.com. The service communication e-mails are essential to our registering you for service and to our continuing provision of services to you. Therefore, you may not opt out of receiving these e-mail messages.

Hosting Zoom will not, however, sell, trade, or otherwise disclose your personally identifiable information unless we are authorized or legally required to do so, or in the case of imminent physical harm to any person. On those Hosting Zoom sites where you may provide Hosting Zoom with credit card, electronic payment service, or other ordering information via the Web, Hosting Zoom protects and secures this information by employing commercially customary Web-based security and encryption protocols, an example of which is the Secure Socket Layer (SSL). On those sites where you voluntarily offer any feedback, data, answers, questions, comments, suggestions, ideas or the like, Hosting Zoom will treat that portion of the information as non-confidential and non-proprietary and, except as otherwise expressed in this privacy statement, Hosting Zoom assumes no obligation to protect such information from disclosure.

**3\. Non-Personally Identifiable (Generic) Information.**

In general, Hosting Zoom gathers some generic information automatically. Generic information does not reveal the identity of the visitor. It usually includes information about the Internet address assigned to your computer, the number and frequency of visitors, and the Hosting Zoom sites visited. Hosting Zoom gathers this information for the limited purpose of determining customer service and Web site needs. We accomplish this by using certain technologies, including “cookies” (a technology that can be used to provide the visitor with tailored information about Hosting Zoom services). Hosting Zoom does not combine information collected in this way with any personally identifiable information. You can set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie and you can refuse it. However, refusing some cookies may make it impossible to use or navigate the Hosting Zoom Web site properly. 

**4\. Your Hosting Zoom-Hosted Web Site, Bulletin Boards, Chat Rooms and Third Party Sites.**

Information that you disclose in a public space, including on any bulletin board, chat room, or Web site that Hosting Zoom may host for you as part of your Hosting Zoom services, is available to anyone else who visits that space. Hosting Zoom cannot safeguard any information you disclose in these locations. Additionally, Hosting Zoom Web sites may contain links to sites that belong to third parties unrelated to Hosting Zoom. Hosting Zoom cannot protect any information you may disclose at these sites and recommends that you review the privacy policy statements of those sites you visit. 

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. 

The Live Chat system that Hosting Zoom uses for customer support is a one-on-one chat. Hosting Zoom owns or licenses the Live Chat software and operates it on Hosting Zoom’s server and network. No third party collects any information that you provide through the Live Chat system. Hosting Zoom may retain and use logs of the Live Chat sessions for any of the following purposes:

•

| to analyze and resolve system problems;  
---|---  
  
•

| to compile and update frequently asked questions (FAQ) and entries in the customer support Knowledge Base;  
  
•

|  to report problems to and obtain technical support from Hosting Zoom’s vendors, suppliers, or service providers;  
  
•

| to train personnel providing support to customers via Live Chat;  
  
•

| to evaluate the job performance of personnel providing support to customers via Live Chat;  
  
•

|  to measure the effectiveness of Live Chat in providing support to customers;  
  
•

| to improve the quality and effectiveness of Live Chat in providing support to customers; or  
  
•

|  to perform any other internal task related to providing services to Hosting Zoom customers, provided that performance of the task does not require disclosure of any of the contents of a chat session without the customer’s prior permission.  
  
**5\. Exceptions and Limitations.**

Notwithstanding the foregoing and in compliance with applicable laws, Hosting Zoom (i) cooperates fully with state, local, and federal officials in any investigation relating to any content (including personal or private electronic communications transmitted to Hosting Zoom) or purported unlawful activities of any user of the Hosting Zoom Service, and (ii) takes reasonable measures to protect its proprietary rights. For the limited purposes of accomplishing such cooperation and measures and in compliance with applicable laws, Hosting Zoom may be required to disclose personally identifiable information.

In addition, Hosting Zoom may elect to monitor the areas of communication of any kind (i) to satisfy any law, regulation, or government request; (ii) if such disclosure is necessary or appropriate to operate Hosting Zoom’s business; or (iii) to protect the rights or property of Hosting Zoom or others. 

**6\. Sale or Transfer of Hosting Zoom’s Stock or Assets.**

In connection with the potential or actual sale or transfer of any of its interest in www.hostingzoom.com, and other sites owned by Hosting Zoom, and any of the assets or stock of the company, Hosting Zoom reserves the right to sell or transfer your information (including, but not limited to, name, address information, and other information you provided to Hosting Zoom) to a third party that (i) concentrates its business in Web hosting or communication products or services; (ii) agrees to be Hosting Zoom’s successor in interest with regard to the maintenance and protection of information collected and maintained by Hosting Zoom; and (iii) agrees to the obligations of this privacy statement. To the extent it is practicable to do so, this paragraph shall also apply in the event of any bankruptcy proceedings involving Hosting Zoom.

In the event that Hosting Zoom plans to transfer your information to a third party incident to a potential or actual sale of any of Hosting Zoom’s assets or stock, or incident to any bankruptcy proceedings involving Hosting Zoom, Hosting Zoom will:

• Notify you by e-mail, at the e-mail address then on file for your account, at least thirty (30) days prior to the transfer taking place; and  
• Give you the opportunity to decide whether you wish for your information to be transferred to the third party. Please note, however, that if you choose not to allow your information to be transferred to the third party, you may have to terminate or cancel your service with Hosting Zoom. At the time of providing notice to you of the upcoming transfer of information to a third party, Hosting Zoom will tell you whether you will have to terminate or cancel your service, should you decide not to allow Hosting Zoom to transfer your information to the third party.

**7\. Applicable Laws.**

AS A MATERIAL CONDITION OF USING THIS WEB SITE OR HOSTING ZOOM’S HOSTING SERVICES, OR BOTH, CUSTOMER AND HOSTING ZOOM AGREE THAT THE USE OF THIS SITE IS BOUND AND GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF THE STATE OF TEXAS AND OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, REGARDLESS OF WHERE CUSTOMER MAY RESIDE, ACCESS THE INTERNET, OR CONDUCT HIS, HER, OR ITS BUSINESS.

MOREOVER, CUSTOMER ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES THAT HOSTING ZOOM RECEIVES AND STORES PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION ON SERVERS LOCATED WITHIN THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. FURTHERMORE, CUSTOMER ACKNOWLEDGES AND AGREES TO SUCH FLOWS OF HIS OR HER PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION ACROSS BORDERS FROM HIS OR HER COUNTRY TO THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.

SPECIAL NOTICE TO CUSTOMERS LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.

Hosting Zoom’s Web site and services are operated by Hosting Zoom, Inc., a corporation existing in the State of Texas, United States of America. Hosting Zoom’s site and services can be accessed by visitors and customers from countries around the world. Such countries may have differing laws with respect to Internet communications, the formation of contracts, consumer protection issues, privacy, and the transfer of personally identifiable information.

**8\. Changes in this Privacy Statement.**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes in this privacy statement, on the home page, and in other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

**9\. Contact Us.**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: privacy@hostingzoom.com, or at our postal address:

Hosting Zoom  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
11205 Bellaire Blvd., Suite B-28  
Houston, TX 77072

**10\. Access to Personally Identifiable Information.**

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update it by making the change on our member information page or by e-mailing our Customer Support at cs@hostingzoom.com.

**11\. Sharing of Information.**

**_Agents_**

We use an outside credit card processing company to bill you for services. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any purposes other than to bill you for our services.

**_Service Providers_**

We use other third parties to provide various additional services for you on our Web site. When you sign up for the additional services, we will share certain elements of the information you provide to us as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

The following table discloses basic information about the service providers with whom we may share your information. For each service provider, we tell you

•

| The provider’s name;  
---|---  
  
•

| The type of service that provider provides to Hosting Zoom or to you;  
  
•

| The information that we share with that service provider;  
  
•

| How the service provider collects your information, which may involve our sending the information to the service provider via a secure Internet link; and  
  
•

| How the service provider is allowed to use your information.  
  
Please note: In most cases, the third party service provider has its own posted privacy policy. Hosting Zoom does not control the operations of any third party service provider and makes no representations or warranties about any third party service provider’s compliance with its own posted privacy. For each service provider, we include the URL of that service provider’s home page so that you can read their privacy policy or contact them with any questions you have about their practices for collecting, using, and disclosing information they gather through their Web site or online services.

**Name of Provider** | **Type of Service Provided to Hosting Zoom or to Customer** | **Elements of Information Shared with Provider** | **How the Provider Collects Your Information** | **How the Provider is Allowed to Use Your Information**  
---|---|---|---|---  
**Authorize.net** | Credit card processor gateway | • name  
• address  
• credit card information  
• telephone number  
| We provide Authorize.net with this information when you fill out the order form on HostingZoom.com. The information is transmitted securely over the Internet. | Authorize.net has their own privacy policy regarding their use of the information we provide to them. 

Please contact Authorize.net to learn the details of their privacy policy.

www.authorize.net   
  
**PayPal** | Payment processor | None. | All payment transactions are processed on PayPal’s secured Web site. | Please contact PayPal to learn the details of their privacy policy. 

www.paypal.com   
  
**Miva Merchant** | Shopping cart software | • e-mail address  
• telephone number  
• domain name  
| We provide this information via an online form at Miva’s website. | We provide the information to Miva so we can install a licensed copy of the Miva Merchant shopping cart software on the your domain. 

Miva stores the customer information in their license database to keep track of Web sites with Miva licenses.

Please contact Miva to learn the details of their internal policies for collecting, using, and disclosing the information.

www.miva.com   

**GeoTrust** | SSL certificate provider that provides you with a SSL certificate.  | • name  
• address  
• e-mail address  
• domain name  
• telephone number  
| We provide this information via an online form at GeoTrust’s Web site. | Please contact GeoTrust to learn the details of their privacy policy. 

www.geotrust.com   

**eNom** | Domain registration | • domain name  
• customer name  
• postal address  
• telephone number  
• e-mail address  | We provide this information to eNom when you sign up for services with us and choose to register an Internet domain name. Your information is transmitted securely over the Internet. | We provide the information to eNom so they can register domain names for you. 

Please contact eNom to learn the details of their privacy policy.

www.enom.com
